<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FACER2VM</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/</link><description>Recent content on FACER2VM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2018 FACER2VM</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 10:15:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://facer2vm.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semantic Scene Interpretation</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/semantic-scene-interpretation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 16:04:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/semantic-scene-interpretation/</guid><description>Professor Josef Kittler presented an invited talk on Semantic Scene Interpretation at the Decentralised Computing and Applications in Business, Science and Engineering 2018 conference held at Jiangnan University, Wuxi, China on 20-21 October 2018.</description></item><item><title>Multimodal and Cross-modal Person Re-identification</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/multimodal-and-cross-modal-person-re-identification/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 12:00:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/multimodal-and-cross-modal-person-re-identification/</guid><description>Professor Josef Kittler attended Global Congress on Biometric Identification 2018 held at Shenzhen, China on 19 October where he presented a key note talk on Multimodal and cross-modal person re-identification.</description></item><item><title>Unconstrained Face Recognition at the EAB</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/unconstrained-face-recognition-at-the-eab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:15:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/unconstrained-face-recognition-at-the-eab/</guid><description>Prof Josef Kittler presented the EPSRC funded FACER2VM project on unconstrained face recognition at a joint meeting of the European Association for Biometrics (EAB) and the German Teletrust Biometrics Working Group held in Darmstadt on 26 September.</description></item><item><title>IEEE FG 2018 Workshop on Dense 3D Reconstruction of 2D Face Images in the Wild</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/fg2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 15:14:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/fg2018/</guid><description>News 01-FEB-2018: The evaluation script of the competition is available via https://github.com/patrikhuber/fg2018-competition. You have to use the script and the provided 7 3D facial landmarks for evaluation. You also should send us back the average error of the reconstructed 3D face for each 2D image.</description></item><item><title>NHK filming at CVSSP</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/nhk-filming-at-cvssp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/nhk-filming-at-cvssp/</guid><description>During the weekend, the Japanese TV Broadcaster NHK came to film an experiment in face matching, comparing the performance of our face recognition system with that of a super recogniser, an individual with exceptional ability to recognise faces, whose company provides services to the UK police in analysing CCTV videos.</description></item><item><title>Face and soft biometrics recognition for smart cities applications</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/face-and-soft-biometrics-recognition-for-smart-cities-applications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/face-and-soft-biometrics-recognition-for-smart-cities-applications/</guid><description>Prof Josef Kittler participated in the 3rd IEEE International Smart Cities Conference held at Jiangnan University, Wuxi, China on 14-17 September 2017. He presented a keynote talk on &amp;quot;Face and soft biometrics recognition for smart cities applications”.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Attention-controlled Cascaded Shape Regression Exploiting Training Data Augmentation and Fuzzy-set Sample Weighting</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/dynamic-attention-controlled-cascaded-shape-regression-exploiting-training-data-augmentation-and-fuzzy-set-sample-weighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/dynamic-attention-controlled-cascaded-shape-regression-exploiting-training-data-augmentation-and-fuzzy-set-sample-weighting/</guid><description>We present a new Cascaded Shape Regression (CSR) architecture, namely Dynamic Attention-Controlled CSR (DAC-CSR), for robust facial landmark detection on unconstrained faces. Our DAC-CSR divides facial landmark detection into three cascaded sub-tasks: face bounding box refinement, general CSR and attention-controlled CSR.</description></item><item><title>Efficient 3D Morphable Face Model Fitting</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/efficient-3d-morphable-face-model-fitting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/efficient-3d-morphable-face-model-fitting/</guid><description>3D face reconstruction of shape and skin texture from a single 2D image can be performed using a 3D Morphable Model (3DMM) in an analysis-by-synthesis approach. However, performing this reconstruction (fitting) efficiently and accurately in a general imaging scenario is a challenge.</description></item><item><title>Smile, you&#39;re on camera, and it knows who you are</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/smile-youre-on-camera-and-it-knows-who-you-are/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/smile-youre-on-camera-and-it-knows-who-you-are/</guid><description>Smile, you&amp;rsquo;re on camera, and it knows who you are
BBC, 7 February 2017</description></item><item><title>Facial Recognition for Enhanced Security Applications</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/facial-recognition-for-enhanced-security-applications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/facial-recognition-for-enhanced-security-applications/</guid><description>Professor Kittler visited New York University of Abu Dhabi (NYUAD) in the United Arab Emirates where he presented a keynote lecture on “Facial Recognition for Enhanced Security Applications” on 7 January 2017.
The invited talk was opened to general public.</description></item><item><title>The Surrey Face Model</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/the-surrey-face-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/the-surrey-face-model/</guid><description>This page is concerned with the availability and downloading of the 3D morphable face models created at the Centre of Vision, Speech and Signal Processing at the University of Surrey. The models are available in these resolutions: 29587, 16759, 3448 and 1724 vertices.</description></item><item><title>Unconstrained face recognition: Approaches to face normalisation</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/unconstrained-face-recognition-approaches-to-face-normalisation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/unconstrained-face-recognition-approaches-to-face-normalisation/</guid><description>This two-day brainstorming workshop explores the various approaches to unconstrained face recognition. From model-based face normalisation methods to end-to-end deep learning based methods. Also video-based approaches, such as 3D face reconstruction and 3D model fitting, will be addressed.</description></item><item><title>3D Morphable Face Model and its Applications (at AMDO 2016)</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/3d-morphable-face-model-and-its-applications-at-amdo-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/3d-morphable-face-model-and-its-applications-at-amdo-2016/</guid><description>Professor Josef Kittler presented an invited paper on 3D morphable face model and its applications at the International Conference on Articulated Motion and Deformable Models 2016, held at Palma, Mallorca during 13-15 July 2016.</description></item><item><title>Advancements in Face Research: A Conversation Between Humans and Machines</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/advancements-in-face-research/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/advancements-in-face-research/</guid><description>The event will cover new and emerging techniques in the area of face research and analysis, providing a means of discussing your research to get feedback from similar fields. This also provides you with an opportunity to brain storm ideas on how to further the current state of the art.</description></item><item><title>Real-time 3D Face Super-resolution from Monocular In-the-wild Videos</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/real-time-3d-face-super-resolution-from-monocular-in-the-wild-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/real-time-3d-face-super-resolution-from-monocular-in-the-wild-videos/</guid><description>A fully automatic approach to real-time 3D face reconstruction from monocular, 2D, in-the-wild videos is presented.
We use a low-resolution 3D Morphable Face Model to obtain a semi-dense shape and combine it with a fast median-based super-resolution technique to obtain a high-fidelity textured 3D face model.</description></item><item><title>Extending NMF to 3D Registered Data</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/extending-nmf-to-3d-registered-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/extending-nmf-to-3d-registered-data/</guid><description>The use of non-negative matrix factorisation (NMF) on 2D face images has been shown to result in sparse feature vectors that encode for local patches on the face, and thus provides a statistically justified approach to learning parts from wholes.</description></item><item><title>3D Morphable Face Model and its Applications</title><link>https://facer2vm.org/posts/3d-morphable-face-model-and-its-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://facer2vm.org/posts/3d-morphable-face-model-and-its-applications/</guid><description>3D Morphable Face Models (3DMM) have been used in face recognition for some time now. They can be applied in their own right as a basis for 3D face recognition and analysis involving 3D face data.</description></item></channel></rss>